<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milki Way Blog</title>
    <description>The blog of Mick &amp; Alki, aka the Milki Way Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.milkiway.it/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.milkiway.it/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 12:00:38 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 12:00:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pour des éditorialistes marketing-free</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pour-des-éditorialistes-marketing-free&quot;&gt;Pour des éditorialistes marketing-free&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dans son article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2017-07-10/the-dark-side-to-macron-s-bright-idea-in-france&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dark Side to Macron’s Bright Idea in France&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/asymmetricinfo&quot;&gt;Megan McArdle&lt;/a&gt; a une conclusion intéressante, qui mérite d’être entendue : il est possible que Macron manœuvre pour renforcer le pouvoir de l’exécutif face au pouvoir législatif de l’Assemblée. Le gouvernement par ordonnance sur la réforme du code du travail semble aller dans ce sens. Mais les arguments qu’elle avance pour défendre sa thèse sont très peu convaincants. À croire qu’elle cherche plus à sensationnaliser qu’à penser ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sur-la-réduction-du-nombre-de-députés&quot;&gt;Sur la réduction du nombre de députés&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L’idée que 400 députés rendrait un député moins redevable auprès de ses électeurs me semble limité.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Il est d’abord mathématiquement douteux. Sur la base d’un électorat de 30 millions d’électeurs, 577 députés représentent en moyenne 52 000 électeurs chacun. Passer à 400 députés augmenterait ce nombre à 75 000 électeurs. Écouter 75 000 électeurs serait donc impossible quand en écouter &lt;em&gt;seulement&lt;/em&gt; 52 000, fonctionnerait parfaitement ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elle avance ensuite que moins de députés permet d’arriver à des décisions plus rapidement. Soit. Nous y reviendrons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sur-la-réduction-du-nombre-de-mandats-et-la-dose-de-proportionnelle&quot;&gt;Sur la réduction du nombre de mandats et la dose de proportionnelle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selon McArdle, une dose de proportionnelle rend le corps législatif moins capable de se mettre d’accord sur quoi que ce soit. Soit, mais cela va en contradiction avec son argument précédant que moins de députés aide la prise de décision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quant à sa position sur le renouvellement des députés, pourquoi les députés sortiraient-ils de nulle part, sans connaissance du contexte de l’Assemblée ? Chaque député dispose d’une équipe et il pourrait donc y avoir des passerelles et des passages de connaissance entre chaque mandat. Elle oublie également de parler des problèmes de corruption et de clientélisme des députés accrochés à leur mandat pendant des décennies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All these ideas are, in fact, favorites of exactly the class of people that Macron represents and typifies: educated cosmopolitans of a technocratic bent, who think that most important problems can be solved by twiddling the system’s rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a l’impression qu’elle réclame ici une révolution avant qu’on se rende compte qu’elle est partisane d’un immobilisme total des modes de gouvernance. Encore une contradiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;À sa question :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Popular parties should hold more power.
Who could possibly disagree with such an obvious principle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simove Weil a apporté une jolie réponse dans sa &lt;em&gt;Note sur la suppression générale des
partis politiques&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sur-sa-posture&quot;&gt;Sur sa posture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McArdle fait preuve d’un cinysme agaçant. Elle accepte sans broncher les défauts de fonctionnement des gouvernements (le “the devil they know”), en soupçonnant toute idée de transformation de naïveté infantile (ie “sadly, the real world, as so often happens, has declined to cooperate with our happy imaginations”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elle se rend compte que la démocratie ne fonctionne pas, mais s’en accomode par exemple quand l’absence de proportionnelle empêche le Front National d’avoir beaucoup de députés. Ce genre de raisonnement relève plus de l’opportunisme et du calcul électoral plus que de la démocratie et de la justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Il me semble donc qu’elle souhaite davantage la polémique que la critique argumentée. Et évite de bonnes questions qui seraient :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quel est le nombre idéal d’électeurs qu’un député peut représenter ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quel est le nombre idéal de députés pour une assemblée performante ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La représentativité d’un député est-elle bien assurée, tant en prise d’information auprès de ses électeurs qu’en restitution de ses prises de parole et des ses actions à l’Assemblée ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comment une carte électorale peut-elle être juste ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.milkiway.it/politics/2017/08/25/marketing-free-opeds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.milkiway.it/politics/2017/08/25/marketing-free-opeds.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One week in North Vietnam</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;one-week-in-north-vietnam-just-do-what-we-did&quot;&gt;One week in North Vietnam: Just do what we did!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you have one week in Vietnam, not sure what to do, and just want to have an awesome, chill, beautiful and delicious vacation?  And don’t feel like spending hours scouring the internet and comparing 878934 tours that all look the same?
Then don’t think too much, just do what we did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-we-are&quot;&gt;Who we are&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two American women friends in our early 30s who hadn’t seen each other in a while.  We decided to meet up in Vietnam for one week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-were-looking-for&quot;&gt;What we were looking for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A chill, fun week to spend some quality time together.  Delicious food, fascinating culture, and nature and beauty.  Not really looking to party, but ok for a little bit of that if the opportunity presented itself — which it sort of did… 😃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-did&quot;&gt;What we did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6-days/6-nights: 2 days in Hanoi, 2 days in Sapa, and 2 days in Halong Bay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;21/04 (Thurs): Arrive in Hanoi early morning.  Spend the day in Hanoi (museums &amp;amp; food tour).  Night train to Lao Cai/Sapa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;22-23/04 (Fri/Sat): 2-day/1-night trek &amp;amp; homestay with Sapa O’Chau.  One night in Sapa homestay, one night in night train back to Hanoi.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24/04 (Sun): Spend the day in Hanoi (explore, massage, night market, cool bars), night in Hanoi.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25-26/04 (Mon/Tues): 2-day/1-night trip to Halong Bay.  One night on boat in Halong Bay, last night in Hanoi.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;27/04 (Wed): Fly out Wednesday morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;budget&quot;&gt;Budget&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam is crazy cheap.  I’d say we went “mid-range” on everything we did, and ended up spending about $400-450/pp for the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;did-we-get-what-we-were-looking-for&quot;&gt;Did we get what we were looking for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely.  And we let you know below what we would do differently (mainly Day #2 in Hanoi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-logistics&quot;&gt;General logistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tour-agency&quot;&gt;Tour agency&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sapaochau.org&quot;&gt;Sapa O’Chau&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
We found them on the internet and contacted them to organize a trek in Sapa.  They ended up organizing everything for Sapa and Halong Bay:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Train and shuttle to/from Sapa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sapa trek (2d/1n)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transport to/from Halong Bay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Halong Bay cruise (2d/1n) with Gray Line Cruises (originally it was Lavender Cruises, and it changed somewhere along the way which was not very clear, and we didn’t ask questions and it was fine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People told us we could just book everything in Hanoi and we’d probably get cheaper prices, but we were so happy to have booked ahead of time to avoid the hassle of visiting countless agencies in Hanoi and trying to negotiate.  And turns out we got a way better deal than other passengers on our cruise.  Shhh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up paying $76 for the train and shuttle to Sapa r/t, $50/pp for the Sapa trek, and $110 for Halong Bay (all-inclusive) = $236.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hotel-in-hanoi&quot;&gt;Hotel in Hanoi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com.sg/Hotel_Review-g293924-d2303643-Reviews-New_Vision_Hotel-Hanoi.html&quot;&gt;New Vision Hotel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Amazing service.  The people working there were extremely kind and helpful.
The breakfast was surprisingly copious and delicious.
Central location in the Old Quarter near the lake.
Basically, great value for the money.  We paid $15/night.  For two people.
The rooms were decent, clean, comfortable, and quiet with good air-conditioning.  Not high-luxury, but again, great value for the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;airport&quot;&gt;Airport&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel (New Vision) ended up organizing our airport transport ($20 each way).  We definitely recommend organizing a pick-up service ahead of time because there are a lot of taxi scams.  You can get cheaper than $20 (probably $10-15), but we liked our hotel, so we just went with them.  The ride to/from the airport is a good 45min so make sure to plan accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visa&quot;&gt;Visa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need a visa, make sure to do it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vietnamvisapro.net&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; (and have ids photos ready!) and we would totally recommend paying the extra $15 to do the “fast track” service. Otherwise, you’ll be sitting in the airport waiting for 1.5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moneytipping&quot;&gt;Money/tipping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The currency is the Vietnamese Dong (VND).
The exchange rate is about $1=23,000 VND, 1€ = 25,000 VND (April 2016)
It’s sometimes hard to do conversions quickly, so have some benchmarks in mind:
— A Pho soup will cost about 35,000-60,000 VND (~$1.5-2.5)
— A coffee about 25,000-50,000 VND (~$1-2)
— Museums: 30,000-40,000 VND ($1.3-$1.7)
Again, things are cheap so if you want to avoid the hassle of stressing over money, just don’t think too hard, you might be paying $0.50 extra from time to time, that’s ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tipping&quot;&gt;Tipping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never figured out the tipping situation, we got massages one day and weren’t sure if we were supposed to tip, so we left 20,000 VND per person.  They made it very clear that they did not appreciate our tip…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-around-in-hanoi&quot;&gt;Getting around in Hanoi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanoi is pretty walkable but beware in the Old Quarter, there are no sidewalks.  Actually there ARE sidewalks, but they are completely useless.
Also, crossing the street seems terrifying at first.  But the key word is CONFIDENCE.  Just go for it.  They know how to get around you.
You can also take taxis but be careful because we got scammed going from the train station to our hotel.  We didn’t totally figure out how to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yea, I recommend asking the hotel how to deal with tipping and taxis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seasonweather&quot;&gt;Season/Weather&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went in April 2016.  And had pretty good weather.  High 80s and sunshine.  There were some surprise rainstorms that caught us off guard.  And Hanoi did get almost unbearably hot and humid one day.  But generally speaking, no complaints about the weather.
The original plan was to go to Cambodia.  Until we found out that April is the hottest month in Cambodia and temperature averages are in the high 90s/100s Fahrenheit (38-40 Celsius).  South Vietnam is similar to Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Vietnam however, is much more temperate during this period. Apparently it gets cold in the winter months (Dec-March).  And then extremely hot and rainy in the summer months (Jun-Sep).  So yeah, to sum it up, it seems the best time to visit North Vietnam is April/May or Oct/Nov (we did good yay!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shopping&quot;&gt;Shopping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I would avoid shopping (trying to buy souvenirs, clothes, etc) in Hanoi.  Unless you like the “crowded and stressful market / constant negotiating atmosphere”.
If you are like me (don’t want stress) but still want to buy some souvenirs and gifts for people, think about buying Hmong bags in Sapa.  And/or there were some “poster” shops that were a little less crazy in Hanoi.  And/or — the most simple option: just shop at the airport.  It wasn’t that much more expensive and SO much more of a relaxing experience.
Gift ideas: Hmong bags, bamboo bowls, communist propaganda notebooks, and Weasel poop coffee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hanoi---sapa---halong-bay-the-details&quot;&gt;HANOI - SAPA - HALONG BAY: THE DETAILS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hanoi&quot;&gt;Hanoi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good:&lt;/strong&gt; Museums.  Food tour.  Massage.  The lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bad:&lt;/strong&gt; “Wandering the streets”.  Trying to shop.  Sunday market.  Taxis&amp;amp;Tipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first day in Hanoi (Thursday), we visited museums and did a food tour.  It was awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The museums.  They are super interesting (lots of communist propaganda rhetoric), cheap, and air-conditioned.  We went to the Hoa Lo Prison Museum, Army Museum, and the Women’s Museum.  And walked by Ho Chi Minh’s museum (it was closed when we went, if you want to go inside, make sure to look at the hours).  And the Temple of Literature.
If you’re not a museum person and just want to do one, I would recommend the prison museum.
*Food tour.  We did the 5pm 3-hour &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hanoistreetfoodtour.com&quot;&gt;Hanoi Street Food Tour&lt;/a&gt;, before jumping on our night-train to Sapa.  It’s maybe a bit cheesy but a great way to discover Hanoi, the food, and some cool restaurants.  $20.  It’s right near the hotel, so we just booked it in the morning for the evening tour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our second day in Hanoi (Sunday), we explored the Old Quarter, got a massage, went to the Sunday night market, and then went to some cool bars &amp;amp; restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wandering/exploring in Hanoi: I don’t recommend it.  Walking in Hanoi is stressful and uncomfortable.  Make sure you have a destination.  And do not plan to just “wander” for a couple of hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Sunday market: Also, not recommended.  Crowded and stressful.  But if you have market FOMO, just plan to go for 30 min to check it out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The massage: We went to a place near our hotel (I threw out the brochure so I don’t remember the name 😔 ).  The 1-hour massage was good and cheap (240,000VND= $10), but again, figure out what is a good tip so you don’t walk out feeling like they hate you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some cool places to hang out / get drinks:
*
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com.sg/Restaurant_Review-g293924-d2216014-Reviews-The_Hanoi_Social_Club-Hanoi.html&quot;&gt;Hanoi Social Club&lt;/a&gt; — Really pretty decor, great music, vegetarian food, relaxing atmosphere.  Great place to hang out with your journal or catch some live music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com.sg/Restaurant_Review-g293924-d3588861-Reviews-Bar_Betta-Hanoi.html&quot;&gt;Bar Betta&lt;/a&gt; — Free beer nights on Wednesday and Sunday! 😃 Again, a really cool place with a roof terrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yea, if we could do the second day again, I’d recommend:
Morning: hang out by the lake, have a coffee and read/write
Lunch: go to one of the places on the food tour, or any one of the numerous local Pho’ or Banh My (= easy, delicious sandwich) places
Afternoon: Get a massage, take a nap, and then head to the Hanoi Social Club for an afternoon tea.
Evening: Grab a quick bite somewhere, and then head to Bar Betta for some drinks from 8-10pm.  If you’re like us and that’s enough partying, head back to the hotel.  If not, continue onto the Beer Corner for some more partying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sapa&quot;&gt;Sapa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good:&lt;/strong&gt; Amazing hikes and views, an awesome guide, and just a wonderful homestay family experience (delicious food, medicinal baths, really cute kids, getting drunk on rice wine and singing non-stop…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bad:&lt;/strong&gt; Be prepared for rain!  And Hmong women following you and trying to sell you stuff on the hike.  But to be honest, it wasn’t that bad.  They were super cute and smiley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we had one more day in Vietnam, I would use it in Sapa.  It’s so incredibly beautiful.  And peaceful.  And unique.
For the hike, we were four women (us + 2 women from Singapore) with one guide, Pay.  Pay was AWESOME.  His English was really good.  He was super funny.  And man, he loved to sing (he just needs a bit of rice wine to get started).
We did the Red Dao Homestay Trek which was perfect for us.  Physical but not too strenuous.  Enough time to soak in the experience and relax (especially in the funny medicinal baths).  Delicious.  And fun.
We were hesitating at first between this trek and one of the motorbike tours.  In the end, we opted for the trek AND on the second day, we had time to rent motorbikes for a couple hours (we asked Pay and Sapa O’Chau just organized that too).  That was awesome.  Do that.  😃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;halong-bay&quot;&gt;Halong Bay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good:&lt;/strong&gt; Incredible views, delicious food, really nice rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bad:&lt;/strong&gt; Too many activities planned, expensive on-boat drinks, and you feel like you’re part of a “tourist-factory” being shuttled in and out of everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have liked to visit Halong Bay in a more “off the beaten track” kind of way, but not sure it’s possible.  At least not in a easy, affordable, laid-back way.  So the tour we did was fine.  You just need to zone out all the cheesy tourist planning, music, etc.  Or embrace it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advice: there are a lot of activities scheduled (caves, hike, kayak,…).  They are nice, but if you have this vision of just vegging out on the top deck of the boat and reading/sleeping/doing yoga, do that!  No need to FOMO.  You will have an incredible experience even if you never step off the boat.  Also, bring a big bottle of water or two, to avoid paying 3x the price for half the water (this being said, we’re still talking $1.5/ bottle).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, ENJOY.  EAT.  RELAX.
And if you haven’t seen “Good Morning Vietnam”, do that now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hanoi-spots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanoi Spots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hanoi-streets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanoi Streets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sapa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sapa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/halong.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Halong&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.milkiway.it/trips/2016/05/14/one-week-in-north-vietnam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.milkiway.it/trips/2016/05/14/one-week-in-north-vietnam.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>trips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Weekend in Cinque Terre</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-weekend-in-cinque-terre&quot;&gt;A Weekend in Cinque Terre&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-weekend-itinerary-which-we-highly-recommend&quot;&gt;Our weekend itinerary (which we highly recommend!)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friday: Arrive in Pisa at 20h30, walk around city, dinner and sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saturday: Visit Pisa, train to Vernazza, lunch in Vernazza, hike from Monterosso to Vernazza, dinner &amp;amp; sleep in Vernazza&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sunday: Hike from Vernazza to Corniglia, train to visit Manarola and Riomaggiore, and back to Vernazza to pick up our bags.  Then train back to Pisa.  Dinner in Pisa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-recommendations-of-where-to-eat&quot;&gt;Our recommendations of where to eat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pisa: Drinks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/bar.pisa&quot;&gt;Bar Mocambo&lt;/a&gt;, cool little book-lined bar with good music, good people and a great happy hour!  Dinner at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Pizzeria-Le-Scuderie-Pisa/189791677738694&quot;&gt;Le Scuderie&lt;/a&gt;, amazing meter-long (and cheap) pizza.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cinque Terre: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilpiratarooms.com/&quot;&gt;Il Pirata delle 5 terre&lt;/a&gt; (Vernazza) for breakfast, lunch and/or dinner (doesn’t have the views, but it has the best food - esp the croissant with ricotta, no joke — and the “Cannoli brothers” are hilarious and excellent conversationalists).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ristorantebelforte.it/&quot;&gt;Belforte&lt;/a&gt; (Vernazza) for lunch or dinner (amazing views and good food).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-to-sleep&quot;&gt;Where to sleep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pisa: sorry can’t help you here, we weren’t big fans of our B&amp;amp;B.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cinque Terre: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.larosadeiventi-vernazza.it/&quot;&gt;La Rosa dei Venti&lt;/a&gt; in Vernazza - clean, quite, lovely, and Giuliana is great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-there-and-around&quot;&gt;How to get there and around?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting to 5T: Fly to Pisa and then take a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lefrecce.it/B2CWeb/search.do?%20&quot;&gt;train&lt;/a&gt; to 5T - super convenient and easy.  I think you can do the same from Genoa.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting around in 5T: Hike, train, or boat.  &lt;em&gt;No need for a car&lt;/em&gt;.  In fact, it’s more of a burden than a convenience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-do-in-5t&quot;&gt;What to do in 5T?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Even in October, 5T is overly crowded with tourists.  It’s still amazingly magical.
Hiking between the villages is INCREDIBLE and the best part of visiting Cinque Terre. The trails are challenging at times, but relatively short, so don’t give up!  And make sure to catch “Jean-Pierre”,  with a lemon products stand between Monterosso and Vernazza selling his delicious lemonade, limoncello, grappa, wine…..
If it rains, the trails might be closed, which is a big bummer…
Don’t get overly excited about the food, you will eat well— but it’s not Sicily.
Besides hiking and eating, there’s not much to do.  Just relax.  And enjoy the immense beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.milkiway.it/trips/2015/11/01/weekend-cinque-terre.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.milkiway.it/trips/2015/11/01/weekend-cinque-terre.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>trips</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
